<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Gatsby Starter Blog RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Just a place to store my blogs, for now]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 16:01:10 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Google Summer of Code - My work At VideoLAN]]></title><description><![CDATA[My work at Google Summer of Code, to simply explain is: enabling dynamic
loading for wasm32-unknown-emscripten. To understand it, we need to…]]></description><link>null/gsoc/my-work-in-gsoc-at-videolan/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">null/gsoc/my-work-in-gsoc-at-videolan/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;My work at Google Summer of Code, to simply explain is: enabling dynamic
loading for wasm32-unknown-emscripten. To understand it, we need to delve
into how VLC&apos;s plugins are loaded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All vlc modules are declared in the source code using the series of macro
that starts with vlc_module_begin() and ends with vlc_module_end().&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;vlc_module_begin()
    set_shortname(N_(&quot;hello&quot;))
    set_description(N_(&quot;Hello World Module&quot;))
    set_capability(&quot;dummy&quot;, 0)
    set_callbacks(Open, Close)
vlc_module_end()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this example callbacks we define how the module is going to be initiated.
We give it name and capability (category) and how the module will be
closed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we see the definition vlc_module_begin macro, we will find that
it is expanded into a function named vlc_entry which takes a callback
vlc_set and opaque as input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let us look into bank.c. In case of shared loading, in module_InitDynamic
we find that the function is loaded from a dynamic plugin file using dlopen.
Then using dlsym, the vlc_entry function is searched and resolved.
In case of static module, there is a global list of static entries
named vlc_static_modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both cases, upon finding the entry function, which we know takes a callback,
it is passed into the vlc_plugin_describe function. From here,
the entry function is called with the callback vlc_plugin_desc_cb
and opaque. Where opaque, in this context is a newly initiated
vlc_plugin_t instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we look into vlc_plugin_desc_cb we can see that there is a switch
statement, that switches a property and based on the property it runs
some code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the entry function now has the ability to use the callback vlc_set
to invoke vlc_plugin_desc_cb and do various things like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;vlc_set (opaque, NULL, VLC_MODULE_CREATE)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To simplify this call, there are helper functions like vlc_plugin_set,
vlc_module_set, vlc_config_set. But they all in the end invokes this.
This way the plugin describes itself and all its capabilities until
it hits the vlc_module_end ie. the return statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But where is the point that decides whether to load with dynamic module
or shared module? To answer this we have to look into the function
module_loadPlugins. This function itself is called from libvlc_new
at some point which is exposed to the front end. During compilation
there is a configuration variable named HAVE_DYNAMIC_PLUGINS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My work is based on this, to get &quot;HAVE_DYNAMIC_PLUGINS&quot; enabled for
wasm32-emscripten. Which will cause module_loadPlugins to call
AllocateAllPlugins which recursively looking for the modules in the
given path passed via environment variables or other methods from the
front end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now to enable this I had to make changes into libtool to allow
it inform it about how to &quot;compile&quot; shared modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While working on this, I came accross an interesting problem. You see
VLC uses GNU Autotools to create their compilation script, like most
other C/C++ projects. The compilation process is simple, if all
dependencies are installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First you bootstrap with ./bootstrap
Then you configure, with ./configure [--enable-params] [--disable-params]
[other params]
And finally you compile, using GNU/Make, with the command &apos;make&apos;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the configure step, among various enable/disable parameters, there
is one parameter called &quot;shared&quot;. This allows the modules to be compiled
as dynamic libraries, making them dynamic linkable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, to enable dynamic linking for wasm32-unknown-emscripten I had to just
do this one thing: add --enable-shared to the configure parameters,
right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wrong! Turns out even if we use --enable-shared in case of wasm32-unknown-emscripten
it does static compilation! I first realized this when I tried
--enable-vlc with --enable-shared just to see how it turns out. And
the configuration fails with the error:
&quot;VLC is based on plugins. Shared libraries cannot be disabled.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something is wrong! This is not supposed to happen, I have tried with
x86_64-linux host, and it works perfectly, then why not in case of
emscripten? For some reason, shared libraries can not be enabled!
Time for some investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what is wasm32-unknown-emscripten?
For that, you have to know what cross compilation triplet is. Briefly saying,
it is &lt;Architecture&gt;-&lt;Vendor&gt;-&lt;Operating System&gt;, so here wasm32 is the
architecture here, emscripten is the Operating System taken to be running
on the browser. VLC.js is basically vlc media player ported to web assembly,
running with Emscripten in browser, hence we use this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the first thing I did was enable building of vlc binaries,  with
--enable-vlc, as vlc binaries can not be built without dynamic loading
enabled. There has to be a check there, that makes sure that shared
modules are enabled.  Opening the configure script and searching for
&quot;VLC is based on plugins&quot;, we indeed find the condition there:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if test &quot;${enable_shared}&quot; = &quot;no&quot; -a &quot;${enable_vlc}&quot; != &quot;no&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, something must have caused enable_shared to be no, But what is it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something must have assigned enable_shared to be no, so let&apos;s search
for &quot;enable_shared=no&quot;, and just few lines before the above line, we
find that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;test no = &quot;$can_build_shared&quot; &amp;#x26;&amp;#x26; enable_shared=no&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the value of enable_shared came from can_build_shared, so now we
search for &quot;can_build_shared=no&quot; to find out that its value came from
the variable dynamic_linker. And it turns out the value of dynamic_linker
is pre-assigned based on host_os. For example, if host_os is android,
dynamic linker is &quot;Android linker&quot; and so on. There seemed to be only
one purpose of this variable, that is to indicate whether a dynamic linker
exists for that particular host_os. Which does not exist for the host_os
I am targetting, &quot;emscripten&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the name, &quot;Android linker&quot; for android has to come from somewhere.
The configure script itself is generated from various configure.am files
when running the bootstrap script as mentioned earlier. So, I make a quick search:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git grep -r &quot;Android linker&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only to find nothing. So this value does not exist in the repository as
a configuration file or anything, rather the value came from outside the
repository. My mentor Alexandre Janniaux was very helpful to point out
that the value comes from libtool, and what we can do at this point is to
hack libtool and add dynamic_linker for emscripten at libtool/m4/libtool.m4
and use that custom libtool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in libtool.m4 there it was, the &quot;Android linker&quot; for the host
linux*android. Taking inspiration from how android section was implemented,
we added a new host_os named emscripten, with dynamic_linker to be
&quot;Emscripten linker&quot;, and bingo! After rebootstrapping with the new libtool
the configuration script ran successfully without switching to static mode
silently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what is libttool?
Libtool is a generic library support script that hides the complexity of
using shared libraries behind a consistent, portable interface. Different
compilers take different flags, commands or approaches to compile shared
libraries. Therefore compiler front end becomes inconsistent. Which in terms,
forces us to use too many unnecessary conditionals in Makefiles. To fix
this issue, Libtool was developed, it handles the differences internally
while giving a consistent front end that we can use for the Makefiles,
enabling us to compile for any other targets whenever needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, we configured emscripten host in libtool to make compilation
compatible with various features in Emscripten compiler that is different
from Clang or GCC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By now we already know where to change for emscripten host. So later is
pretty straightforward. That is to understand what is needed for successful
compilation and configure libtool&apos;s source accordingly.
Look around the source! There are examples everywhere.
Still we need to make sure what we need and carefully enable the required
features corrosponding to the compiler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, since my shared compilation is not being forcefully disabled,
now, I can try to figure out from the error and warning messages which
compiler options should be removed and which are to be added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, at this stage, configuring with --enable-shared and
compiling it gives the warning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;emcc: warning: linking a library with `-shared` will emit a static 
object file. This is a form of emulation to support existing build 
systems.  If you want to build a runtime shared library use the 
SIDE_MODULE setting. [-Wemcc]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now from the documentation of emscripten we do find out that SIDE_MODULE
is emscripten&apos;s way of compiling a code as shared module, as opposed
to -shared. So, we have to use that instead. But how do we add this
to libtool?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this we use the LT_TAGVAR method to modify archive_cmds. This simply
edits the part of libtool that creates dynamic library archives to answer:
&quot;Which parameters will I run to create the archive?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.. m4 ::
_LT_TAGVAR(archive_cmds, $1)=&apos;-s SIDE_MODULE=1&apos;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Libtool has default way of naming each library archives and shared
objects, which include, name, relese and extension. If we want we
can change this default behavior by changing library_name_spec and
soname_spec.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.. m4 ::
library_names_spec=&apos;$libname$release$shared_ext&apos;
soname_spec=&apos;$libname$release$shared_ext&apos;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can also tell libtool which command parameter is
necessary for position independent code setting &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;_LT_COMPILER_PIC&lt;/code&gt;. For
our purpose, we  needed &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;-fPIC&lt;/code&gt;. However, now, you can try inspecting
this variable for Windows section! As we know Windows does not use
position independent code, but uses a very different method to achieve
shared loading. That&apos;s the beauty of libtool! With all these
complexities taken care of here, we do not need to worry about  it in
compile time. With this we can easily configure cross compilation for
all platforms with a single build script!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, at your build path (The path from where you run your configure
script) there is an interesting file named &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;config.status&lt;/code&gt;.
This file is created when you run the configure script. Observing this
file, you can find some interesting keys. Keys like: soname_spec,
archive_cmds, lt_prog_compiler_pic. Sounds familiar right? We just
worked with these keys above, in libtool.m4!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This file helped me a lot while debugging libtool.m4, hope it helps
you as well ;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the libtool.m4 ready for emscripten compilation, we can now finally
initiate compilation. Libtool will configure itself and put necessary
flags for us. At this point everything compiled successfully, till the
compilation of binaries. Then this error shows up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.. log ::
error: undefined symbol: libvlc_new (referenced by
top-level compiled C/C++ code)
warning: _libvlc_new may need to be added to
EXPORTED_FUNCTIONS if it arrives from a system library&lt;br&gt;
Here I just showed the error for libvlc_new function only. But this error
occurs in case of all the functions that are exposed to the front end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why does it occur? Well during compilation of shared modules, some
compilers demand another flag that tells which functions to be exported
i.e. can be seen by the user. Different compiler implements it differently,
emscripten has its own way of doing this as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case of  We can use -s EXPORTED_FUNCTIONS to provide the function
names. Like this:
&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;emcc code.c -s EXPORTED_FUNCTIONS=_function1,_function2,_function3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can provide them through  a file as well:
&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;-s EXPORTED_FUNCTIONS=@path/to/file.sym&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The file has to be a text file. Within this: functions are provided
like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;_function1
_function2
_function3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing so will expose function1, function2, function3 from code.c.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice that, the actual function name is function1, but while when exporting,
we use the name _function1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, different compiler was implemented with different standards.
Some compilers do not even take file name, some compilers do not add _
before their function names. Some compilers do not even need to export
functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now libtool handles this very interestingly. It takes the symbol file
path as input with --export-symbols option. In the backend in libtool.m4
we can catch this file path in the export_symbol variable.
Then the commands saved at archive_expsym_cmds is used to compile the file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conventionally, this file contains function list like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;function1
function2
function3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That looks great! But there is a big problem. Emscripten takes shared
function input prefixing with _. But conventionally we do not have that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve this I took the following steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take the input file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add _ before each line.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save it to another file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use that file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how to do all these while assigning it to
&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;_LT_TAGVAR(archive_expsym_cmds, $1)&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out _LT_TAGVAR has a cool way to instruct it to run a command
while assigning a string. You can use it like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&quot;Your Command Here ~ Normal string here that you Intended to Keep&quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this purpose, libtool also has its own wrapper on &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;sed&lt;/code&gt; named
&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;$SED&lt;/code&gt; that can be used in the strings. During build this will be converted
into a runnable &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;sed&lt;/code&gt; command. &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;$SED&lt;/code&gt; is same as &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;sed&lt;/code&gt;, except it uses &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;|&lt;/code&gt; in place of &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;/&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the final implementation becomes something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;_LT_TAGVAR(archive_expsym_cmds, $1)=&apos;$SED &quot;s|^|_|&quot; $export_symbols &gt;$output_objdir/$soname.expsym~$CC -sSIDE_MODULE=2 -shared $libobjs $deplibs $compiler_flags -o $lib -s EXPORTED_FUNCTIONS=@$output_objdir/$soname.expsy&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To break down:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We take the input file with &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;$export_symbols&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We use sed to add _ before every function name:
&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;$SED &quot;s|^|_|&quot; $export_symbols&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We save it to &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;$output_objdir/$soname.expsym&quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We preceed it with the ~ to indicate that command part has ended, its time to take the actual string.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the string, we can use &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;$output_objdir/$soname.expsym&lt;/code&gt; instead of&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;$export_symbols&lt;/code&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may ask here, we have already handled -shared in archive_cmds. So why
handle it here again? The answer is: If a file has functions to export,
Libtool will use archive_expsym_cmds, otherwise, Libtool will use
archive_cmds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And with this, our libtool is ready for emscripten. We just create a
patch out of it, and instruct our emscripten  build script to always
apply our patch and compile libtool in case of shared compilation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also it turns out that several features of emscripten are not quite
ready yet for this purpose. For example, EM_JS is not supported
in emscripten shared modules. EM_JS is a macro that allows one to
execute JavaScript inside web assembly. Also there are issues with
linker in emscripten linker for compiling C++ sources with shared
modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also there is a bug in emcc that, which leads it to &quot;forget&quot; which
libraries are linked with it while compiling main module with shared
modules if a shared module does not depend on other shared modules,
but the other shared module depends on it. In this case: emcc simply
forgets the shared modules that are passed to it with parameter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reproducer for this bug is available &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.videolan.org/Labnann/emscripten-library-forget-test&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To fix this issue I looked into the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;process_dynamic_libs&lt;/code&gt; method that
is called by emcc to resolve all the dynamic libraries and found out
that there is a Breadth First Search of libraries that forgets to add
root node to the visited or &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;seen&lt;/code&gt;. So I solved this issue by marking
the file as seen when being visited, IE: whenever popped from the queue
in the BFS implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, emscripten&apos;s implementation of opendir only works
with WasmFS. WasmFS is a virtual filesystem for file operations
provided by emscripten. WasmFS is not linked with the server, so
actual directory search is not conducted by opendir.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To mitigate this, I added a JavaScript method that mounts the plugin
directory to WasmFS. The method named mountVLC is provided with a script\file named &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;mountvlc.js&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which calls the function recursivelyDownloadFiles(baseURL, directoryPath)
method that downloads the files and directories and places them on the
wasmFS recursively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how do we recreate the folder structure with files? Being a
simple static http file server: It can not provide us with the information
about the directory structure. So, from the front end we have know
idea where to send the request to get the correct file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we do know, that if we send request to a particular valid directory
we can have a list of files and directories as a html named Directory Listing
document provided the directory does not have index.html.
The filename and list can be found as inner text of &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag or as
value of href. Same is applied for directories, except, all directory
strings end with /.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, all we need is a regex, that can be used to strip away all the
html and keep the file name and directories only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspecting a HTML response, one can easilly tell that the href contains
name of a particular directory of a file, so all we need is a regex that
can do the job for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the list of all the files and directories, now we can send
fetch request to all of the files, and in case of directories
(list element that ends with /) we can call FS.mkdir to create the path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FS is a module that emscripten provides us to interact with the WasmFS.
It has all the methods that makes it very easy to do file operations:
like readFIle, writeFile, readdir etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To download a file, I used the fetch api provided by the browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;async function downloadAndStore(url, path) {
  const response = await fetch(url);
  const content = await response.blob();
  let data = new Uint8Array(await content.arrayBuffer());
  FS.writeFile(path, data);
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may be wondering, the data I just wrote into WasmFS, how am I so sure
that this data was not altered. Like I used all the conversions of the
data in the code above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is a valid question! So I created a sha256sum checker for WasmFS to
test our download method. If the checksum of a downloaded matches with the
one residing on the server, success!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;async function calculateFileChecksum(filePath) {
  const fileContent = await FS.readFile(filePath, {encoding:&apos;binary&apos;};
  const buffer = new Uint8Array(fileContent).buffer;
  const hashBuffer = await crypto.subtle.digest(&apos;SHA-256&apos;, buffer);
  const hashArray = Array.from(new Uint8Array(hashBuffer));
  const hashHex = hashArray.map(byte =&gt; byte.toString(16).padStart(2, &apos;0&apos;)).join(&apos;&apos;);
  return hashHex;
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The browser provides us the sha256sum function, which can be called like this:
crypto.subtle.digest(&apos;SHA-256&apos;, content)
Yes it supports other algorithms for checksum as well! But I like sha256sum.
So, we read the file from filepath as a binary, convert it into a Uint8Array
as required by digest(). The output then needs to be converted from buffer
to Uint8Array to JavaScript Array which can be used to convert the result to
a hex string. You can read more about this in &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/SubtleCrypto/digest&quot;&gt;MDN&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this method I tested couple of binaries that matches with the sha256sum
of the original file from the server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And with that, the vlc.html is able to call libvlc_new and module loading
begins!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Google Summer of Code Journey:  Hacking Libtool: Part 1]]></title><description><![CDATA[While working in VLC.js for VideoLAN in Google Summer of Code 2023, I came
accross an interesting problem. You see VLC uses GNU Autotools to…]]></description><link>null/libtool/gsoc-libtool-part1/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">null/libtool/gsoc-libtool-part1/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;While working in VLC.js for VideoLAN in Google Summer of Code 2023, I came
accross an interesting problem. You see VLC uses GNU Autotools to
create their compilation script, like most other C/C++ projects. The
compilation process is simple, if all dependencies are installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First you bootstrap with ./bootstrap
Then you configure, with ./configure [--enable-params] [--disable-params]
[other params]
And finally you compile, using GNU/Make, with the command &apos;make&apos;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the configure step, among various enable/disable parameters, there
is one parameter called &quot;shared&quot;. This allows the modules to be compiled
as dynamic libraries, making them dynamic linkable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, to enable dynamic linking for wasm32-unknown-emscripten I had to just
do this one thing: add --enable-shared to the configure parameters,
right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wrong! Turns out even if we use --enable-shared in case of wasm32-unknown-emscripten
it does static compilation! I first realized this when I tried
--enable-vlc with --enable-shared just to see how it turns out. And
the configuration fails with the error:
&quot;VLC is based on plugins. Shared libraries cannot be disabled.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something is wrong! This is not supposed to happen, I have tried with
x86_64-linux host, and it works perfectly, then why not in case of
emscripten? For some reason, shared libraries can not be enabled!
Time for some investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What and why wasm32-unknown-emscripten?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For that, you have to know what cross compilation triplet is. Briefly saying,
it is &amp;#x3C;Architecture&gt;-&amp;#x3C;Vendor&gt;-&amp;#x3C;Operating System&gt;, so here wasm32 is the
architecture here, emscripten is the Operating System taken to be running
on the browser. VLC.js is basically vlc media player ported to web assembly,
running with Emscripten in browser, hence we use this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the first thing I did was enable building of vlc binaries,  with
--enable-vlc, as vlc binaries can not be built without dynamic loading
enabled. There has to be a check there, that makes sure that shared
modules are enabled.  Opening the configure script and searching for
&quot;VLC is based on plugins&quot;, we indeed find the condition there:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if test &quot;${enable_shared}&quot; = &quot;no&quot; -a &quot;${enable_vlc}&quot; != &quot;no&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, something must have caused enable_shared to be no, But what is it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something must have assigned enable_shared to be no, so let&apos;s search
for &quot;enable_shared=no&quot;, and just few lines before the above line, we
find that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;test no = &quot;$can_build_shared&quot; &amp;#x26;&amp;#x26; enable_shared=no&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the value of enable_shared came from can_build_shared, so now we
search for &quot;can_build_shared=no&quot; to find out that its value came from
the variable dynamic_linker. And it turns out the value of dynamic_linker
is pre-assigned based on host_os. For example, if host_os is android,
dynamic linker is &quot;Android linker&quot; and so on. There seemed to be only
one purpose of this variable, that is to indicate whether a dynamic linker
exists for that particular host_os. Which does not exist for the host_os
I am targetting, &quot;emscripten&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the name, &quot;Android linker&quot; for android has to come from somewhere.
The configure script itself is generated from various configure.am files
when running the bootstrap script as mentioned earlier. So, I make a quick search:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git grep -r &quot;Android linker&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only to find nothing. So this value does not exist in the repository as
a configuration file or anything, rather the value came from outside the
repository. My mentor Alexandre Janniaux was very helpful to point out
that the value comes from libtool, and what we can do at this point is to
hack libtool and add dynamic_linker for emscripten at libtool/m4/libtool.m4
and use that custom libtool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in libtool.m4 there it was, the &quot;Android linker&quot; for the host
linux*android. Taking inspiration from how android section was implemented,
we added a new host_os named emscripten, with dynamic_linker to be
&quot;Emscripten linker&quot;, and bingo! After rebootstrapping with the new libtool
the configuration script ran successfully without switching to static mode
silently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What is libttool?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Libtool is a generic library support script that hides the complexity of
using shared libraries behind a consistent, portable interface. Different
compilers take different flags, commands or approaches to compile shared
libraries. Therefore compiler front end becomes inconsistent. Which in terms,
forces us to use too many unnecessary conditionals in Makefiles. To fix
this issue, Libtool was developed, it handles the differences internally
while giving a consistent front end that we can use for the Makefiles,
enabling us to compile for any other targets whenever needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, we configured emscripten host in libtool to make compilation
compatible with various features in Emscripten compiler that is different
from Clang or GCC. The details will be in part two!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article we learned and reviewed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How projects are typically compiled and built and a bit of inner
mechanisms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debugging build scripts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to get started with adding a new host target to libtool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for the part two! And stay safe.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Linux Kernel Bug Fixing - My Experience]]></title><description><![CDATA[For the past one year, I knew about Linux Kernel Mentorship Program
which I had been wishing to join. And this summer as my university
asks…]]></description><link>null/lkmp-experience/my-experience2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">null/lkmp-experience/my-experience2/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;For the past one year, I knew about Linux Kernel Mentorship Program
which I had been wishing to join. And this summer as my university
asks me for gaining industry level knowledge, I decided why not now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On 8th May, I applied for the Mentorship program. &quot;Will they take
me?&quot; I wondered. Next two days I did not notice anything to happen.
On May 10, I went to read the emails and there I realized I have
tasks assigned to me with the deadline being on May 18. Most of the task
description scared me and I was like, I have to do these in one week?!
If you have tough looking enemy in video games at very first mission,
you are like &quot;Relax! It is the first mission, it must be easy.&quot; I jumped
with this similar motivation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you have guessed, these tasks aren&apos;t just any other screening tasks,
they are a great learning opportunity which teaching me to boot, build,
break, test, patch the kernel as well as learning to get familiar with
the release cycle and communications. I worked a lot because to reach
my target of getting the screening tasks done properly, I had a lot to
learn in just one week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On May 27, I got the email.
&quot;Congratulations! We are pleased to let you know that you have been
accepted as a mentee to the Linux kernel Bug Fixing Summer 2022 mentorship.
The program administrator will contact you with the next steps.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And my journey as a Linux Kernel Mentee started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux Kernel Bug Fixing is a Linux Kernel Mentorship Program designed
for newcomers in the open source community. I have learned so many
aspects about computer science, lower level programming, open source
development, working with community, software engineering, software
project management, importance of defining and maintaining core
principles in a project in the past three months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most important things I learned is using the docs and codebase
itself to learn to work. My mentors always encouraged the documentations
and the source code that gives relevant information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the parts of the codebase is so
simple and fascinating. Some codes have some really funny comments.
It is really satisfying, to see the code building up from top to down
at the core level of hardware, which we normally do not see in other
software projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To try and understand this bug I used this tool named ftrace. I was
fascinated by the result seeing the internals of how so many functions
getting executed one after another just to run a simple reproducer. If
you are interested about ftrace you can learn about it here:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kernel.org/doc/Documentation/trace/ftrace.txt&quot;&gt;https://www.kernel.org/doc/Documentation/trace/ftrace.txt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However my tool of choice was GDB and Qemu. Qemu is an emulator where
I run the kernel image and using Qemu&apos;s debugger I connect gdb to it
and start debugging. If the error path is too mysterious for me in that
I use ftrace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned, even if C is not an Object Oriented Language, it is possible
to write clean codes with it. It does not have Class, but it does
have structs. The higher level modules define and provide structs
that have void function pointers. The lower level modules implement
the functions and inject the pointers into the structs. This way the
Dependency Injection Principle is kept intact. The lower level module
itself defines how it needs to be initiated, used, freed and higher
level module just calls them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another interesting thing here to take from this project is error
handling. If an error occurs, a negative error code is propagated
from deep within the low level to the higher level. Here is an example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;struct dev* dev_create(params) 
{
 struct *dev = kmalloc(sizeof(struct dev), params.flag)
 if (!dev)
    return ERR_PTR(-ENOMEM);
// initiate things
 ...
}


int dev_create_user ()
{
 ...
 struct dev = dev_create(params);
 if (IS_ERR(dev))
    return (PTR_ERR(dev));
 ...
 //do other things.

}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This way error gets propagated to the surface until it is handled.
In many cases goto is used for handling errors if it is a bit complex.
Yes, if used correctly, goto is great for clean coding error handlers
and not evil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programmers often insert &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;BUG_ON&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;WARN_ON&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;ERROR_ON&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;pr_debug&lt;/code&gt;
etc which only logs when Kernel is compiled with config like Dynamic
Debug is turned on. These not only increases readability of the code,
they help fuzzers to try and trigger unintended program paths to find
out bugs automatically. The kernel has some other dynamic debugging
tools within it too, like KASAN which is used to detect out of bounds
access and use after free, KCSAN for finding data races. Also KMSAN
which is not in the upstream yet, for finding uninit variables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bugs I tried to solve are triggered by syzkaller dynamically or
static analysis tools like coverity uncovered some potential bugs.
So my task description was easy, try to fix the bugs and let the
mentors know if any difficulties are faced. Everyday I went to Syzbot,
look through the issues that are probably valid and choose one or two
bugs that has reproducer and try to find out what causes the problem
and what could be the solution to the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the link to Syzbot, if you are interested:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://syzkaller.appspot.com/upstream&quot;&gt;https://syzkaller.appspot.com/upstream&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here is the Coverity link for Linux Bugs:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://scan.coverity.com/projects/linux&quot;&gt;https://scan.coverity.com/projects/linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux Kernel is a complicated project. Often It was hard to come up with
the right question to ask the mentors. So I had to self study, buy one
or two books just to learn what could be the right term to use. But
that is not all. The thing about open source is, it is not just the
designated mentors that help, rather everyone helps. I send a patch
that might be solution and people working from that area comments on
my patches. I get to ask questions about why they think so and they
are really helpful and considering enough to answer these questions. This
is one of the most wonderful experiences to me. They do not care about
age, race, gender, ethnicity, color or religion. The open source culture
is truly awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often my fellow mentees did some very cool discussions. Those were
very informative and fun. It was a great experience to meet, learn
and work with people from different parts of the world. Every day I
is something new to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And before I could understand it, the ending of this amazing adventure
arrived. But as our mentor said, the purpose was to get us started,
with Kernel Development and we can always keep contributing to this
wonderful project. So, this is not the ending, rather the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By now I have three patches accepted in Linux and few rejected as well.
With all of them being very informative. And the big news is Linux 6.0
is going to be released soon, with my code running in it too.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Linux Kernel Mentorship Program: How They Prepared Me For Kernel Development Before I Even Got Accepted]]></title><description><![CDATA[There is a general belief, that in an internship, unless it is long
you will spend your time learning, and will probably never get to work…]]></description><link>null/lkmp/how-lkmp-prepares-candidates/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">null/lkmp/how-lkmp-prepares-candidates/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;There is a general belief, that in an internship, unless it is long
you will spend your time learning, and will probably never get to work
in any important ongoing project. Because getting acquainted with a
new project is tough as they are pretty large and combine years of
works.But here in LKMP, I got to send my first patch to production
AKA upstream kernel before I even started. The Linux kernel is the
biggest software project on the planet with over 25 million lines of
code. So how does Linux Kernel Mentorship Program do this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To select the candidate, they give them several tasks to complete. But
unlike anywhere else, they give enough resource materials to learn
and complete the tasks at the same time. This learning phase covers
many important beginner kernel developers guide. So the candidates
who complete the learning phase are almost ready to hack the kernel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To say generally:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Firstly learn how build the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then they teach how to change a small part of the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then teach how to create a new working module.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these learned, candidates are already knowledgeable about where
&quot;things start&quot; and &quot;things end&quot;. Then the mentors encourage the
candidates to: fix some documentation or work on test cases. Fixing
documentation or tests requires research and the candidate is sort
of forced to apply themselves to look into the code to understand the
intention of a code. Therefore the candidate gets to send their
first patch (git diff) to the community before even getting accepted
into LKMP. And thus they get hands on experience on development
process and if the patch is good enough, it gets accepted too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, implementing the process I described up there is not very hard.
This not only efficiently tests candidates if they have the correct
skills for the work, but also gives them flavor of their work. Which
in turns make them curious, confident, passionate and eventually
they contribute in the project.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[New Beginnings]]></title><description><![CDATA[Far far away, behind the word mountains, far from the countries Vokalia and
Consonantia, there live the blind texts. Separated they live in…]]></description><link>null/new-beginnings/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">null/new-beginnings/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Far far away, behind the word mountains, far from the countries Vokalia and
Consonantia, there live the blind texts. Separated they live in Bookmarksgrove
right at the coast of the Semantics, a large language ocean. A small river named
Duden flows by their place and supplies it with the necessary regelialia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;On deer horse aboard tritely yikes and much&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Big Oxmox advised her not to do so, because there were thousands of bad
Commas, wild Question Marks and devious Semikoli, but the Little Blind Text
didn’t listen. She packed her seven versalia, put her initial into the belt and
made herself on the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This however showed weasel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Well uncritical so misled
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this is very interesting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goodness much until that fluid owl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When she reached the first hills of the &lt;strong&gt;Italic Mountains&lt;/strong&gt;, she had a last
view back on the skyline of her hometown &lt;em&gt;Bookmarksgrove&lt;/em&gt;, the headline of
&lt;a href=&quot;http://google.com&quot;&gt;Alphabet Village&lt;/a&gt; and the subline of her own road, the Line
Lane. Pityful a rhetoric question ran over her cheek, then she continued her
way. On her way she met a copy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Overlaid the jeepers uselessly much excluding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But nothing the copy said could convince her and so it didn’t take long until a
few insidious Copy Writers ambushed her, made her drunk with
&lt;a href=&quot;http://google.com&quot;&gt;Longe and Parole&lt;/a&gt; and dragged her into their agency, where
they abused her for their projects again and again. And if she hasn’t been
rewritten, then they are still using her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Far far away, behind the word mountains, far from the countries Vokalia and
Consonantia, there live the blind texts. Separated they live in Bookmarksgrove
right at the coast of the Semantics, a large language ocean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a paradisematic country, in which roasted parts of sentences fly into your
mouth. Even the all-powerful Pointing has no control about the blind texts it is
an almost unorthographic life One day however a small line of blind text by the
name of Lorem Ipsum decided to leave for the far World of Grammar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;According a funnily until pre-set or arrogant well cheerful&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Big Oxmox advised her not to do so, because there were thousands of bad
Commas, wild Question Marks and devious Semikoli, but the Little Blind Text
didn’t listen. She packed her seven versalia, put her initial into the belt and
made herself on the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So baboon this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mounted militant weasel gregariously admonishingly straightly hey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dear foresaw hungry and much some overhung&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rash opossum less because less some amid besides yikes jeepers frenetic
impassive fruitlessly shut&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When she reached the first hills of the Italic Mountains, she had a last view
back on the skyline of her hometown Bookmarksgrove, the headline of Alphabet
Village and the subline of her own road, the Line Lane. Pityful a rhetoric
question ran over her cheek, then she continued her way. On her way she met a
copy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The copy warned the Little Blind Text, that where it came from it would have
been rewritten a thousand times and everything that was left from its origin
would be the word &quot;and&quot; and the Little Blind Text should turn around and
return to its own, safe country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But nothing the copy said could convince her and so it didn’t take long until a
few insidious Copy Writers ambushed her, made her drunk with Longe and Parole
and dragged her into their agency, where they abused her for their projects
again and again. And if she hasn’t been rewritten, then they are still using
her. Far far away, behind the word mountains, far from the countries Vokalia and
Consonantia, there live the blind texts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Silent delightfully including because before one up barring chameleon&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Separated they live in Bookmarksgrove right at the coast of the Semantics, a
large language ocean. A small river named Duden flows by their place and
supplies it with the necessary regelialia. It is a paradisematic country, in
which roasted parts of sentences fly into your mouth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even the all-powerful Pointing has no control about the blind texts it is an
almost unorthographic life One day however a small line of blind text by the
name of Lorem Ipsum decided to leave for the far World of Grammar. The Big Oxmox
advised her not to do so, because there were thousands of bad Commas, wild
Question Marks and devious Semikoli, but the Little Blind Text didn’t listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Wherever far wow thus a squirrel raccoon jeez jaguar this from along&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She packed her seven versalia, put her initial into the belt and made herself on
the way. When she reached the first hills of the Italic Mountains, she had a
last view back on the skyline of her hometown Bookmarksgrove, the headline of
Alphabet Village and the subline of her own road, the Line Lane. Pityful a
rhetoric question ran over her cheek, then she continued her way. On her way she
met a copy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;Slapped cozy a that lightheartedly and far&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The copy warned the Little Blind Text, that where it came from it would have
been rewritten a thousand times and everything that was left from its origin
would be the word &quot;and&quot; and the Little Blind Text should turn around and return
to its own, safe country. But nothing the copy said could convince her and so it
didn’t take long until a few insidious Copy Writers ambushed her, made her drunk
with Longe and Parole and dragged her into their agency, where they abused her
for their projects again and again.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[My Second Post!]]></title><description><![CDATA[Wow! I love blogging so much already. Did you know that "despite its name, salted duck eggs can also be made from
chicken eggs, though the…]]></description><link>null/my-second-post/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">null/my-second-post/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Wow! I love blogging so much already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know that &quot;despite its name, salted duck eggs can also be made from
chicken eggs, though the taste and texture will be somewhat different, and the
egg yolk will be less rich.&quot;?
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salted_duck_egg&quot;&gt;Wikipedia Link&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I didn&apos;t either.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is my first post on my new fake blog! How exciting! I'm sure I'll write a lot more interesting things in the future. Oh, and here's a…]]></description><link>null/hello-world/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">null/hello-world/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This is my first post on my new fake blog! How exciting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m sure I&apos;ll write a lot more interesting things in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and here&apos;s a great quote from this Wikipedia on
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salted_duck_egg&quot;&gt;salted duck eggs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A salted duck egg is a Chinese preserved food product made by soaking duck
eggs in brine, or packing each egg in damp, salted charcoal. In Asian
supermarkets, these eggs are sometimes sold covered in a thick layer of salted
charcoal paste. The eggs may also be sold with the salted paste removed,
wrapped in plastic, and vacuum packed. From the salt curing process, the
salted duck eggs have a briny aroma, a gelatin-like egg white and a
firm-textured, round yolk that is bright orange-red in color.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
      style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; max-width: 630px; &quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/blog/static/8058f3f26913fea3b6a89a73344fe94a/e1596/salty_egg.jpg&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
    style=&quot;padding-bottom: 75.31645569620254%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAPABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFgABAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAMB/8QAFwEAAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEEBf/aAAwDAQACEAMQAAABgik0dXC//8QAGRABAAMBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQACERIy/9oACAEBAAEFAkqW7B5Zox9t8n//xAAXEQEAAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAERJB/9oACAEDAQE/AdVl/8QAFhEBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABEC/9oACAECAQE/AYun/8QAGxAAAQQDAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAECESEiMTL/2gAIAQEABj8CvRjaHMkvIQo//8QAGxAAAwEBAAMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAREhAEGBobH/2gAIAQEAAT8hsTTH203YINmYDPHckkPzQiAnv//aAAwDAQACAAMAAAAQyC//xAAXEQEBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABABEh/9oACAEDAQE/EBHDK6y//8QAGBEAAgMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAERIVH/2gAIAQIBAT8QWiS0j//EABwQAQEAAgMBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAERADEhYYFB4f/aAAgBAQABPxBOzi0NHmChLtHkL9EcWZeCVJ1kcRoVp3lEYcnjEk0ES7/Jn//Z&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
  &gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        alt=&quot;Chinese Salty Egg&quot;
        title=&quot;&quot;
        src=&quot;/blog/static/8058f3f26913fea3b6a89a73344fe94a/828fb/salty_egg.jpg&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/blog/static/8058f3f26913fea3b6a89a73344fe94a/ff44c/salty_egg.jpg 158w,
/blog/static/8058f3f26913fea3b6a89a73344fe94a/a6688/salty_egg.jpg 315w,
/blog/static/8058f3f26913fea3b6a89a73344fe94a/828fb/salty_egg.jpg 630w,
/blog/static/8058f3f26913fea3b6a89a73344fe94a/0ede0/salty_egg.jpg 945w,
/blog/static/8058f3f26913fea3b6a89a73344fe94a/3ac88/salty_egg.jpg 1260w,
/blog/static/8058f3f26913fea3b6a89a73344fe94a/e1596/salty_egg.jpg 2048w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 630px) 100vw, 630px&quot;
        style=&quot;width:100%;height:100%;margin:0;vertical-align:middle;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot;
        loading=&quot;lazy&quot;
        decoding=&quot;async&quot;
      /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also write code blocks here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;js&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; saltyDuckEgg &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;chinese preserved food product&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Number&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Title&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;Year&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Harry Potter and the Philosopher’s Stone&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;2001&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;2002&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;2004&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.github.com/adamschwartz/github-markdown-kitchen-sink/master/README.md&quot;&gt;View raw (TEST.md)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a paragraph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;This is a paragraph.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Header 1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Header 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Header 1
========

Header 2
--------&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Header 1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Header 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Header 3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Header 4&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Header 5&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;Header 6&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;# Header 1
## Header 2
### Header 3
#### Header 4
##### Header 5
###### Header 6&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Header 1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Header 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Header 3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Header 4&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Header 5&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;Header 6&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;# Header 1 #
## Header 2 ##
### Header 3 ###
#### Header 4 ####
##### Header 5 #####
###### Header 6 ######&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit. Aliquam hendrerit mi posuere lectus. Vestibulum enim wisi, viverra nec, fringilla in, laoreet vitae, risus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&gt; Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit. Aliquam hendrerit mi posuere lectus. Vestibulum enim wisi, viverra nec, fringilla in, laoreet vitae, risus.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;This is a header.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is the first list item.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is the second list item.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&apos;s some example code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Markdown.generate();&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&gt; ## This is a header.
&gt; 1. This is the first list item.
&gt; 2. This is the second list item.
&gt;
&gt; Here&apos;s some example code:
&gt;
&gt;     Markdown.generate();&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Red&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Green&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Red&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Green&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Red&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Green&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Red
&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Green
&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Blue

&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; Red
&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; Green
&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; Blue

&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Red
&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Green
&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Blue&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;code goes&lt;/code&gt; here in this line&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt; goes here&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token code-snippet code keyword&quot;&gt;`code goes`&lt;/span&gt; here in this line
&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token bold&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;**&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token content&quot;&gt;bold&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;**&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; goes here&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buy flour and salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mix together with water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bake&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt; Buy flour and salt
&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt; Mix together with water
&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt; Bake&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;code goes&lt;/code&gt; here in this line&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt; goes here&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token code-snippet code keyword&quot;&gt;`code goes`&lt;/span&gt; here in this line
&lt;span class=&quot;token list punctuation&quot;&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token bold&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;**&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token content&quot;&gt;bold&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;**&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; goes here&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paragraph:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Code&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;!-- --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Paragraph:

    Code&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;* * *

***

*****

- - -

---------------------------------------&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;a href=&quot;http://example.com&quot; title=&quot;Example&quot;&gt;an example&lt;/a&gt; link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://example.com&quot;&gt;This link&lt;/a&gt; has no title attr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;a href=&quot;http://example.com&quot; title=&quot;Optional Title&quot;&gt;an example&lt;/a&gt; reference-style link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;This is [an example](http://example.com &quot;Example&quot;) link.

[This link](http://example.com) has no title attr.

This is [an example] [id] reference-style link.

[id]: http://example.com &quot;Optional Title&quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;single asterisks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;single underscores&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;double asterisks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;double underscores&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;*single asterisks*

_single underscores_

**double asterisks**

__double underscores__&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paragraph has some &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;code&lt;/code&gt; in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;This paragraph has some `code` in it.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://via.placeholder.com/200x50&quot; alt=&quot;Alt Text&quot; title=&quot;Image Title&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;![Alt Text](https://via.placeholder.com/200x50 &quot;Image Title&quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>